# Jonathan Ryan Johnson

## **Application Development and Operations Manager**

jon.johnson@ucsf.edu

(650) 516-7401

https://www.jrjohnson.dev



**y** jrjohnson\_

#### **Profile**

Expert in team leadership, development, and psychological safety; enterprise web application development using PHP, Javascript, JSON, SQL and XML; open source contributions and community; modern web standards; cloud systems; accessible web design; automated deployment; continuous integration and system automation.

Becognized for ability to adapt and expand with the growing needs of an organization and learn new skills as

Recognized for ability to adapt and expand with the growing needs of an organization and learn new skills as necessary.

### **Skills**

#### Domain

Working with and Building Diverse Teams
Psychological Safety and People Management
Educational Administration and Curriculum Development
Open Source Community Maintenance and Communication
Organization Architecture and Development
Community Building

#### **Technical**

API Design and Development
Web Application Development
Accessibility
Secure Application Development and Operations
Test Driven Development
Open Source Development
Continuous Integration and Deployment
AWS and Cloud First Architecture

#### **Talks**

Jumping into Deep Work Automagic Deployment with Github Actions Microapps: A Covid-19 Case Study Cut Your Team Some Slack Handling Complicated Tasks with a Chatbot Always Be Updating Career Day at Aragon High School

## **Education**

BA History (Pre-Law)
University of the Pacific
2003

MA Educational Administration
University of the Pacific
2005

# **Sample Code**

PHP: Ilios Symfony Backend API Server

Javascript: Ilios EmberJS Web App I ember-cli-image-transformer I ember-noscript I ember-fontawesome

## **Recent Experience**

## **Teaching and Learning Applications**

Manager 2019-present While still maintaining a focus on technical leadership for the Ilios platform assumed responsibility for the Collaborative Learning Environment and the developers and support staff for CLE systems. Led the campus wide A3 effort to transform the organization and funding model for education at UCSF on behalf of the Committee for Educational Technology; maintained uptime, stability, and security through multiple system

upgrades; seamlessly transitioned to fully remote work; strengthened partnerships with LTG and school technologists during the transition to pandemic remote teaching; proactively advocated for moving our team to the new Educational IT organization and managed the uncertainty and chaos of that transitional while maintaining a rigorous Ilios release schedule and on schedule upgrade of Moodle; served on the Medibiquitous Technical Advisory Group as an API and medical education standards expert.

## **Ilios Curriculum Management Platform**

Technical Lead, Architect **2014–2019** Managed the transition from a code igniter and YUI driven application to a modern Hexagonal Symfony API with an EmberJS frontend for a user-friendly, flexible, and robust web application to collect, manage, analyze and deliver curricular information in Medical Education.

#### **Jazzee Graduate Admissions**

Architect, Developer, Evangilist 2009–2014 Designed and built the Jazzee admissions system to collect and manage graduate applications and payments. Built on an XML API and a revolutionary user customizable form builder with a focus on accessibility, usability, and security. Deployed for admissions at three University of California graduate schools for admissions.